<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Snook.ca</title><description>Life and Times of a Web Developer</description><link>https://snook.ca/</link><item><title>Waited</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/personal/waited</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/personal/waited</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just a few days after writing about the expectation of not getting a vaccine anytime soon, the provincial government seemed to be getting pushback and suddenly they announce availability of the AstraZeneca vaccine for people aged 40+. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news got announced on Sunday. I signed up for half a dozen waitlists on Monday—because a centralized, well-managed system for vaccinations doesn’t exist for some reason. Then heard that it’s better to go into individual pharmacies or call. On Tuesday, I walk into the local pharmacy and get an appointment booked for Wednesday. Sure enough, it is now Wednesday afternoon, less than a week after lamenting the inability to get a vaccine, and I have had my first shot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent much of yesterday thinking that I must’ve misheard or that there was a step that I must’ve missed along the way. I wasn’t &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; going to get a shot today. But I did. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I wait for the second shot, which will likely be in June or July. This feels like a huge step and at the same time, nothing changes. Kids are still doing remote learning. Restaurants are still closed. Cases are still high. I’m still staying home. We’re still in a pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead of being filled with dismay, I’m filled with hope. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 18:25:07 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wait</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/personal/wait</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/personal/wait</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout much of this pandemic, while traumatic, it was comforting that we were all in this together. Now, as many of my American and UK friends get their first vaccinations, they are starting to return to a normal life. They are travelling, they are visiting family, and they are making plans for the summer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Canada, however, vaccines have been slow going and cases are on the rise. Cases per 100,000 has exceeded that of the US for the first time since the beginning of the pandemic. And it is unlikely I’ll be able to receive a vaccine before July. Even receiving one before the end of summer could be questionable, which is disappointing to consider. And now a new stay-at-home order just as the warmer weather has arrived. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am demoralized and demotivated and all I can do is…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wait. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 20:52:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uncanny</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/personal/uncanny</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/personal/uncanny</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’m standing in line at the grocery store. My hands are full of products I don’t recognize but should be sufficient for the next couple days here. I place things on the conveyor belt, hoping the cashier doesn’t ask any questions. Of course, she does. I assume she’s asking if I want a bag and shake my head no. Thankfully, that seemed to answer her question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The few items are rung up and she tells me the total. Again, I don’t understand a word. I glance quickly at the screen to see the total and I pull out a bill large enough to cover it. I have a pocket full of change but it’s going to take me forever to figure out which is what and I don’t want to hold up the line any further. I’ll end up leaving all the change at the hotel before I head home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I head off into the street, checking my phone to confirm directions back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m standing in line at the grocery store. I’m six feet back, on a marked circle, but shifting forwards and backwards to let those moving from aisle to aisle get by. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My glasses fog up ever so slightly and then clear up. They fog up again and then clear. I start holding my breath so as not to have them fog up completely. Maybe if I breath through my nose. Maybe through my mouth? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve grown up in cold winters, scarves wrapped around my head. I usually just take my glasses off. I do so again, careful not to get my hands close to my eyes. I’ll grab some hand sanitizer on the way out. I’ll wash my hands again when I get home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let me spray and wipe down the belt first, sir.” Right. Old routines keep wanting to creep back in but I have to wait. I think to myself that I’ve read studies of how fomite-based virus transfer might not be a big concern. It’s all about the air. Who knows, said more as a statement than a question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stand to the side of the tall plexiglass barrier with my bag at the ready to quickly bag my own groceries. Cashiers aren’t allowed to do it themselves anymore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I no longer leave my cart at the exit, allowing others entering the building to quickly grab my cart. The entrance is now fully separated from the exit, forcing specific lanes of traffic. I take my cart to the mid-lot receptacle to keep the lifecycle of collect-and-clean in check. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bags are placed into the back of the car and I hop into the front. I carefully peel the mask from my face. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything feels surreal. Most things are the same but plenty of things are not. They’re just different enough to create a generalized anxiety. It’s not unusual for me to feel this anxiety when I’m travelling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I feel it when I’m at home. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 21:18:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>That’s Pretty Clever</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/other/thats-pretty-clever</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/other/thats-pretty-clever</guid><description>

&lt;p&gt;I was over at my friend’s place—in the backyard, outside—playing some games. Thankful for the warm summer nights and not looking forward to a pandemic lasting through winter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the games we played was a dice game called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/244522/s-pretty-clever&quot;&gt;That’s Pretty Clever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. We each had our own piece of paper and pen to mark off various items to be scored at the end. The scorecard is very specific to the game and I imagined the pad supplied with the game eventually running out. To which, I wondered, could I build an online version of the scorecard? Even handier would be if it could calculate the scores at the end of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://snook.ca/clever/&quot;&gt;So that’s what I did&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another one of my personal challenges, I gave myself the goal of building this scorecard in under a week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What did I learn?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With personal projects, the fun is often in the constraints we give ourselves. The first of which was time. I probably could’ve completed the task more quickly than the four days I had given myself. Many things, like scoring, turned out to be easier to do than expected. But &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law&quot;&gt;Parkinson’s law comes into play&lt;/a&gt;: projects fill up all of the time allotted to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Progressive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another constraint I gave myself was making this work progressively. If JavaScript is turned off, the page will continue to work as an equivalent of the paper version as all of the boxes are just HTML and CSS. It’s checkboxes, text fields, and radio buttons. Then you add up your score just as you would if you did it on paper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do have JavaScript turned on, then a click of a button will give you your score. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;All in One&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up was deciding to do this as a single page. That meant embedding the CSS, JavaScript, and any assets—in this case, all SVGs—into the HTML. Not really a big deal but to keep size down, I used SVG &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;defs&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;use&lt;/code&gt;d them throughout the page. I needed to do inline SVGs so that I could easily change the colour based on what section they’re in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I relied on simple text and CSS wherever I could, such as using a recycle icon in place of the circular arrows icon from the original game. I ended up with 3 SVGs: the fox, the starburst, and the meeples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping everything in one page meant saving time and bandwidth not having to make multiple requests. The page is only 5.44kb compressed which leaves most of the overhead in the initial handshake with the server versus actual delivery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Scoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally thought the scoring was going to be a sizeable part of the project. I projected the number of lines of code to exceed all of the HTML and CSS put together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I got into it, though, I noticed some patterns that I hadn’t seen in my cursory glance that allowed me to use a simple loop for a couple sections. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could’ve cut down the size by a few lines but I would’ve lost clarity. I appreciate the simplicity, even if a couple &lt;code&gt;forEach&lt;/code&gt; loops are repeated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sloppy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many of my other personal projects like my blog, this particular project is a one-off. I don’t expect to ever come back to this project to update it. As such, the idea of maintainability went completely out the window. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the HTML is reasonably decent—although, I do make some assumptions along the way and I really didn’t take accessibility under consideration. In my defence, the project was for me and not intended for a wider audience, so my apologies to those attempting to use my rather clunky development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was writing the CSS, I’d say to myself, “you should probably name this differently,” but I didn’t listen. Honestly, I was surprised at how few issues I had putting it together. I attribute this to the small size of the project, preventing things from getting out of control. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then in the final minutes of development, it happened. I needed to add &lt;code&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt;. And then another one. And another one. Whoops. Guess I was getting a little too sure of myself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh the things we do to get a job done knowing we’ll never have to deal with it again. (But will curse myself if I ever do.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Grid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS Grid was quite handy. Much of this design was in a grid and it was great to just set up some &lt;code&gt;repeat()&lt;/code&gt; declarations and have everything aligned. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the biggest “trick” I used was using grid within a cell to layer all the positional elements within the center and then shifting them as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.snook.ca/article/badges.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the game is just a checkbox. Click on it to mark it as “completed”. But the starburst, the badge at the bottom, and the greater-than rule are all relational to that checkbox. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.check {
  display: grid;
  place-items: center;
}
.check &amp;gt; * {
    grid-row: 1;
    grid-column: 1;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything that wasn’t the checkbox also got a &lt;code&gt;pointer-events: none&lt;/code&gt; added to it so clicks could still get through to the checkbox. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I’d use a bit of positioning to move things around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.starburst {
    position:relative;
    top: -32px;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Anything else?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to fall into a trap of scope creep. So many features I could add. This scorecard doesn’t stop you from making incorrect inputs. Where something is unlocked elsewhere on the board, it could highlight those moves. Where a move can automatically be made, it could make that move. I could set up the scorecard to be made available offline. I could even create a dice roller. Which leads to my final constraint…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to replicate the game entirely online. If people want to play the game, I hope they buy the game from the publisher and support their work. My project is intended to replicate the scorecard and just the scorecard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://snook.ca/clever/&quot;&gt;The scorecard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 17:31:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Reply via Email</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/rss/reply-via-email</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/rss/reply-via-email</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While I don’t blog nearly as often as I used to and while I removed comments from my site a few years back due to lack of use and the constant barrage of spam, it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; nice to hear from people that either have something nice to say, have a helpful critique, or want to have a dialogue on an interesting topic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanmarcotte.com/wrote/replyin/&quot;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt; have done, I’ve added a “Reply via email” mailto link at the bottom of each article in my RSS feed to making conversation a little bit easier. (I also added the same thing on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca&quot;&gt;The Nook&lt;/a&gt;, for you whisky-minded individuals.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still a fan of RSS, even if I’m not as prolific as I once was. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 15:34:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>An Exploration of Flavour</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/design/an-exploration-of-flavour</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/design/an-exploration-of-flavour</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a screenshot the other day that had a list of projects that I had built over 10 years ago. There was a Flickr app, a Twitter app, a job site, an ad platform. I had forgotten how prolific I was at one time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely fell into a rut there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, though, I’ve been getting back into exploring design and flexing my design and front-end skills on some personal projects. Last year, I launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://fifty.snook.ca/&quot;&gt;Fifty&lt;/a&gt; to document a food adventure. I played around with CSS grids and took inspiration from magazines to create a design I was proud of. Months later, I’m still loading up the site just to stare at it. Feels good, y’all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along those lines, I’ve jumped heavily into the world of whisky. I’ve attended &lt;a href=&quot;https://webwhiskyweekend.com/&quot;&gt;Web Whisky Weekend&lt;/a&gt; for the last fives years, which has been a fantastic way to explore whisky. Last year, we had 150 different bottles. Crazy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over those five years, I’ve been buying bottles and growing my collection at home. I’m up to about 60 bottles. Crazy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to build a site to track my personal library: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Snook Nook&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been fun playing around with new CSS features like &lt;code&gt;clamp()&lt;/code&gt; and trying different grid techniques. If you’re on desktop, check out how “The Snook Nook” font size and letter spacing grow and shrink as you resize the page to ensure the title always stays on the same line and feels balanced with the page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, I borrowed heavily from print magazines and I’m really happy with how the design is coming together. Yes, there are still some rough corners and I’m continuing to iterate on the design. I did the same thing with Fifty. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through two other designs before I settled on this one and found myself hesitating to build it until I thought the design was &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt;. Of course, perfection is the enemy of done, so I was happy this design was good enough to feel okay putting out something that wasn’t perfect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoy whisky, I’d love it if you followed along. If you don’t, maybe you’ll enjoy me fumbling over words trying to describe what this golden liquor tastes like. Come visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://nook.snook.ca/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Snook Nook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 02:31:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Overlapping Header with CSS Grid</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/html_and_css/overlapping-header-with-css-grid</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/html_and_css/overlapping-header-with-css-grid</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have this design. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.snook.ca/grid-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;Green header with rounded body overlapping the header&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, I’ve done this with negative margins. The header has a height that adds a bunch of padding to the bottom and then the body gets a &lt;code&gt;margin-top: -50px&lt;/code&gt; or whatever the design calls for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I knew I was going to be using Grid for the shell of this page, I wondered if there was an easy way to do this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set up the page using three columns and four rows. The centre column is where the header, body, and footer reside. The left and right columns are the gutter, which—based on this particular design—I want to collapse on small screens. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The header goes in the first row and the footer in the last. (Firefox has a great Grid visualizer, by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.snook.ca/grid-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;The design with Firefox’s grid lines on&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first instinct to getting this to work was to have the header span rows 1 and 2 and have the body span 2 and 3. The problem here is that the header content won’t push the body down if things need to reflow in the header. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can mitigate this by adding enough padding to the header equal to the height of the overlapping row. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;grid-template-rows: auto 8em 1fr auto;

.shell-header {
  padding-bottom: 8em;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that’ll definitely work just fine. However, because I had collapsing margins for this design, I wanted the padding for the header to line up with the body. I can use media queries to adjust the padding for small and large screens (as well as the media queries for collapsing the margins). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a different approach that let me leave the padding alone. I added an element for the background colour and stretched that over the first two rows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/* overlap */
.shell:before {
  content: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;;
  grid-column: 1/-1;
  grid-row: 1/3;
  background-color: #063;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I’m using &lt;code&gt;:before&lt;/code&gt;, it should automatically be behind everything else. If I used &lt;code&gt;:after&lt;/code&gt;, it’d be on top and I’d have to use &lt;code&gt;z-index&lt;/code&gt; to get it back behind everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like that, I have an overlapping header. &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/snookca/pen/ExVOWWM&quot;&gt;Check it out on CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 13:37:04 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fancy Zoom Calls</title><link>http://snook.ca/archives/conferences/fancy-zoom-calls</link><guid>http://snook.ca/archives/conferences/fancy-zoom-calls</guid><description>
&lt;p&gt;AKA, how I set up my Sony DSLR to use as a webcam. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you’ve only just woken from a months’ long coma and the first thing you decided to do was read my blog, you’re likely aware of (&lt;em&gt;waves arms around&lt;/em&gt;) this quarantine. I’ve been home and isolated for two months now. Fun times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I’m in a lot of Zoom calls. As a result, I’m envious of the few people with their fancy camera and mic setups. As a result, I decided to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.snook.ca/1159-webcam-pre.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The lowly Mac camera&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The lowly Mac camera&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, here are a list of articles of what other people have done to get this going:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://danmall.me/articles/better-webcam-video/&quot;&gt;Dan Mall’s setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plasticmind.com/0s-and-1s/using-dslr-for-webcam/&quot;&gt;Jesse Gardner’s setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mattstauffer.com/blog/setting-up-your-webcam-lights-and-audio-for-remote-work-podcasting-videos-and-streaming/&quot;&gt;Matt Stauffer’s setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read them? If so, you may notice as I did that every single one of them use the Elgato Camlink. It’s a hardware dongle that allows you to plug in your camera via HDMI and it’ll be recognized as a webcam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool cool cool cool. Here’s the thing: everybody and their grandmother have clearly read the same articles and ordered themselves the Elgato Camlink. As such, they are sold out everywhere. If you’re in the United States, it seems some people have still been able to get their hands on them. Up here in America’s Hat (i.e. Canada), I couldn’t find them anywhere. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had pretty much resigned myself to living with the Mac’s FaceTime camera. Is that so bad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, then I came across a YouTube video that perfectly describes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OCwRY06cAW4&quot;&gt;how to setup a Sony DSLR as a webcam using a piece of free software called CamTwist&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.snook.ca/1159-webcam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The amazing Sony camera&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The amazing Sony camera&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, kinda sorta. It’s a clunky setup that requires me to fire up my camera, then fire up Remote, then fire up CamTwist, then fire up the remote streaming tool of choice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, when I opened up Zoom, it wasn’t recognizing the CamTwist webcam. (Skype seemed to work fine but everybody is using Zoom these days.) Everything I was finding on the web was telling me to downgrade to a previous version of Zoom to allow this to work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, as Zoom tried to fix a bunch of security issues, they decided to lock out any unsigned webcams. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.reddit.com/r/VIDEOENGINEERING/comments/fy7xi3/fyi_zoom_v4610_breaks_blackmagic_capture_devices/&quot;&gt;This is explained in this Reddit thread&lt;/a&gt;.) CamTwist is 10 year old software and isn’t signed. As such, it doesn’t get recognized. To solve this problem, you need unsign Zoom so that it’ll allow unsigned webcams. This feels icky but it worked and since we’re dealing with a global pandemic at the moment, unsigning an app seems like the least of my worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Per the instructions in the Reddit thread, you’ll need to have Xcode installed and then you’ll be able to run this line of code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;codesign --remove-signature /Applications/zoom.us.app/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like that, you’re in business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, like I said, it’s not ideal. You can’t minimize the Remote app or the webcam doesn’t work. You can’t use Spaces or the webcam doesn’t work. You don’t want to resize the Remote app or CamTwist will show the wrong thing. Remote resets its height and width every time its opened, so best not to mess with it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the upside, CamTwist is &lt;em&gt;studio&lt;/em&gt; software, so you can play with effects and text overlays and even cut between multiple video feeds, if you’re feeling overly ambitious. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while not perfect, it’ll do. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:snookca@snk.ms&quot;&gt;Reply via email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description><author>Jonathan Snook &lt;jonathan@snook.ca&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 23:18:50 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>